## Richa Kaur

## **Business Analyst**

Business-minded analyst with an interest in machine learning and demonstrated ability to deliver valuable insight via data analytics and advanced data driven methods. Particularly relied on mathematical and technological background to attain a meaningful solution. Good technical experience in implementing machine learning algorithms.

Rourkela, Odisha

© (+91)9090302071

https://richakbee.github.io/

richabudhraja8@gmail.com

https://github.com/richakbee

https://www.linkedin.com/in/richakaur-931500141/

#### **EDUCATION**

- BTech in Computer Science &
   Engineering (with Honors), 9.1 CGPA
   BPUT, Odisha- 2019
- St. Josephs Convent School, Rourkela (1995-2013), 90 % in X, 89% in XII

#### **SKILLS**

- Tools & Framework Python3, R, , SQL, Tableau, MS office ,Jupyter, Tensorflow, keras , sklearn, AutoML , pandas , Pycaret , Flask, Flutter,Android Studio, Aws/Azure/GCP, MongoDB.
- Techniques Regression,
  Classification , Clustering , Bagging,
  Boosting, Dimensionality Reduction ,
  Hyper Parameter Tuning ,Data
  Visualization ,Exploratory Data Analysis,
  Data Mining , Feature engineering, Data
  Wrangling ,Web Scraping ,ANN , CNN ,
  RNN (basic),NLP (basic) , Transfer Learning
  , Deployment, Advanced Data Analytics.

#### **COURSES & CERTIFICATION**

- <u>Deep Learning Specialization</u>
   Coursera.
- <u>DeepLearning.Al TensorFlow Developer</u>
   <u>Specialization</u>, Coursera.
- Applied Data Science in Python
   Specialization ,University of Michigan
- Descriptive Statistics with R,IIT Kanpur, NPTEL
- Data Mining , IIT Kharagpur ,NPTEL
- Intro to Statistics , Udacity
- Intro to Descriptive Statistics, Udacity
- Intro to Inferential Statistics ,Udacity
- <u>Hands On Tableau A-Z</u>, Udemy
- Tableau Advanced ,Master Tableau for Data Science , Udemy
- Machine Learning , Stanford University.

#### **AWARDS**

 Scholarship awardee for being top of the batch in 2<sup>nd</sup>,3<sup>rd</sup>, 4<sup>th</sup>, 5<sup>th</sup> semester

# **STRENGTHS**

- Excellent Oral &Written communication
- Committed to Lifelong Learning
- ability and interest in working in a fast-paced, ambiguous and rapidly changing environment

#### **Hobbies**

- Fitness : Yoga ,Strength Training @gym
- Adventure : Hiking , Trekking , Camping
- Book Reading (atleast 10 pages / day)
- Sports:. Carrom, Chess, Badminton (award winning)

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Swiggy

**Business Analyst** 

April 2021- Present

Roles & Responsibilities: -Working for Growth and product analytics of Instamart

in

# NMTechnosol (with @Affine Analytics ) Business Analyst

July 2019 -April 2021

### Roles & Responsibilities: -

- Performed descriptive analysis and provide self-service analytical solutions to strategy global heads of pharma section of a Fortune 10 animal health company.
- Implemented Initial EDA deck and Visualization Dashboard to understand databehavior.
- Performed Advanced analytics, a querying to Derive insights from data.
- Served various on-site adhoc analytical requests , hypothesis testing .
- Developed fully automated reports from concept to product in form of Dashboard (creation, maintenance and story telling with Tableau.)
- Identified KPI for waterfall analysis for bulk purchasing potential of customers.
- Segregated Customers into Loyal ,Switch & new category & Performed Repeat purchase analysis to identify potential loyal customers to improve sales..
- Developed requirements and create requirements documents and process flows.

#### **❖** Data Science Initiative : - (Clustering & analysis for target marketing)

- o Collaborated with different domain experts to ideate & derive initial KPI's.
- $\circ \quad \text{Aggregated Transactional level data to perform in detailed exploratory analysis}.$
- o Derived insights & Performed dimensionality reduction using factor analysis.
- O Used K-means ++ for Clustering & identified 4 clusters in data.
- Visualized Clusters using PCA & performed cluster analysis to generate insights.

#### **Mindfire Solutions**

January 2019 -June 2019

Full Stack Web Developer (Intern)

#### Roles & Responsibilities :-

- Created a Blogging Site from scratch where users can follow people, see posts from them, write, edit, delete their own posts.
- Worked on Bug tracking web app, used by Team Members to assign a Bug Handling job to a particular Member, Track the Status of the Bugs

#### **PERSONAL LEARNING**

- <u>Sentiment Analysis</u>— Worked on a Classification problem to understand sentiment hidden in text & classify if it is positive or negative. (on IMDB movie reviews).
- Back Order Prediction End to End ML application to detect if a product could come short & Order has to be cancelled.(inventory management)
- <u>Big Mart Sales</u> End to End ML application deployed on GCP to predict the sales of an item at a particular Outlet.
- Insurance Fraud Detection End to End ML application deployed on Azure to detectif
  the insurance claim is fraudulent or genuine.
- Image Classification Web app A Flask Object Segmentation app that classifies between cats & dogs images when uploaded by a user. (CNN)
- <u>Digit Recognizer ( A deep learning app on flutter )</u> A its a Deep Learning appthat
  recognizes Digits. Users have Two options: either upload an image of a digit or draw the digit
  on drawing space. CNN Model was created in TensorFlow. ..
- Demand Forecasting (Bike Sharing & Rental) A Regression problem to forecast the numbers of bikes to be rented at any hour of a day .(Kaggle challenge)